# Christopher Jacobs

Fort Wayne, IN 46835 | 260-334-2586 | jacobsc050@gmail.com

## **Summary**

Energetic Graduate Teaching Assistant with a master's degree in mathematics and experience supporting others in research and education. Excellent instructor, project manager and research leader. Built productive relationships with all levels of students and educators.

# **Experience**

#### GRADUATE TEACHER'S ASSISTANT | 08/2020 - Current

#### Purdue Fort Wayne - Fort Wayne, Indiana

- Mentored students in the ability to communicate and do physics
- Improved labs and pedagogical skills weekly with professors of physics
- Guided students through scientific ways of knowing
- Monitored student progress using quizzes and assignments to check for thorough understanding

#### PHYSICS TUTOR AND LAB ASSISTANT | 08/2019 - 05/2020

#### Purdue Fort Wayne - Fort Wayne, Indiana

- Assisted students with developing and applying analytical skills useful for different physics equations.
- Wrote physics problems to help students advance knowledge.
- Encouraged students during emotionally difficult moments in the learning process

### COMPUTERIZED MAINTENCE MANAGEMENT SYSTEM INTERN | 06/2019 - 01/2020

#### Water Pollution Control Plant - Fort Wayne, Indiana

- Began to improve efficiency of working place through app development (Swift and XCode)
- UX development using an extensibility framework (built on Infor EAM database)
- Automated daily data transfer using python

## Research

#### Quantum entanglement - Single Photon Experiments | 08/2019 - Current

Goal: To learn about the quantum nature of photons and explore models of light

- Self-taught material in optics and quantum mechanics
- Set up of experiments to explore ideas in quantum optics including use of spectrometers and interferometers
- Mentored 4 students in conducting research, writing presentations, writing papers, and summarizing pertinent research papers

#### Senior Thesis – Reverse Biased Diodes as Photon Detectors | 12/2019 – 05/2020

- Conducted an experiment, gathered results, and wrote a scientific article
- Integrated, built, and troubleshot an integrating sphere, circuit board, PSoC, Serial inputs, python, and excel to collect and analyze data
- Mentored a high School student in the scientific method and a rigorous scientific experiment

#### **SPAD – Single Photon Avalanche Detection** | 08/2019 – 12/2019

Goal: To make a cost-effective circuit that can be used to detect photons

- Experience in electronics and quantum mechanics
- Designed and fabricated circuit boards

# **Projects**

• Link: <a href="https://github.com/jacobsc050/projects">https://github.com/jacobsc050/projects</a>

## **Certifications**

JavaScript Foundations Gold Badge Coder – 1150 Academy | 05/2018 - 06/2018

- Built a website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Built a recipe generator with use of an API
- Experience with Git Hub, IDEs, collaboration using Stack Overflow
- Built a portfolio using Bootstrap: <a href="https://jacobsc050.github.io/portfolio/">https://jacobsc050.github.io/portfolio/</a>

# **Education and Training**

Purdue Fort Wayne - Fort Wayne, IN | Master of Science

Degree: Mathematics with concentration in physics, Earned: 12/2021

• 3.83 GPA

Purdue Fort Wayne - Fort Wayne | Bachelor of Science

Degree: Physics with minor in Mathematics, Earned: 05/2020

• 3.34 GPA

University North Manchester - North Manchester | 3 Years of Courses (No Degree)

Physics, Mathematics

• 3.73 GPA